Abul Hasanat Sekh GitHub: github.com/abulhasanat abulhasanat.com Medium: medium.com/@hasanat.abul Mobile: +91-9989335052, 8918014140 Skype: abulhasanat

SUMMARY

Seasoned Data Scientist driving transformation with Analytics and Machine Learning with over15 years of experience in building Machine Learning models, Deep Learning models, BigQuary, GCP, Azure, Data Visualization, SQL Server DBA & Developer, Performance Tuning, Web and REST API applications. I have worked with Investment Banks, Startups, and consulted for Technology services companies.

I'm currently working as an Independent Consultant and completed multiple projects on Market Research, Time Series Analysis, AB Testing, Image, and Text Classification.

Area of interest

- Data Analytics, Machine Learning & Deep Learning
- Solution Architect
- Project/Delivery Management

hasanat.abul@gmail.com Electronic City, Bangalore

• SQL Server DBA/Development/Performance Tuning

Top skillst

Python, Numpy, Pandas, Tensorflow, PyTorch, PySpark, SQL Server, Mongo DB, Azure, GCP & AWS

EXPERIENCE

• Independent Consultant

Machine Learning Consultant

Bangalore, India Sep 2019 - present

- Customer Engagement and ML Solutions: Work independently with end customers provide solution. development and support on Machine Learning & Deep Learning
- Web Content Filter: A web content filtering is a solution that would intercept web traffic, have the ability to accurately categorize it, and either allow or disallow based on some config. (CNN, NLP, Google BERT, Web scrapping, DB Scan)
- Structural Classification of Web Pages: An effective way to build relevance and authority signals related to the google search engine algorithm is to get links from other sites to the sites and pages. To find sites that could potentially link to the client's site, user required a similar page's backlinks and determine a strategy for getting the link placed on that page or a similar page.(Random Forest, Web scrapping)
- SQL Server Support: SQL Server Performance tuning and DBA activities
- o Key clients: Compu Solutions, iConnect & Money Geek, USA

• DxC.technology

Bangalore, India

Aug 2016 - Aug 2019

Service Delivery Consultant - IV

Deutsche Bank Account Support: DxC Bionics project is an initiative to reduce efforts on IT infrastructure services by using automation. Data Analytics with Machine learning plays a major role on finding opportunities on automation and incidents reductions.

- ML Framework: Develop an end-to-end framework for training, testing and deployment of Machine Learning models with a team of 3 developers (Python, NumPy, scikit-learn)
- o Data Collection & Preprocessing: Extract & preprocess data from using Web scrapping (Python, BeautifulSoup, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib)
- o Modeling: Develop and implement Neural Network, Timeseries Analysis & Random Forest models to predict new incidents & CI health (Python, scikit-learn, Pandas, NumPy and Keras)
- o SQL Server backend support for Private cloud: Portfolio comprised various technologies on private cloud support and maintenance and SQL Server Customer Support Manager.

• Thomson Reuters

Hyderabad, India Assistant Manager May 2009 - April 2016

o Data Analytics Project: Develop Lead Segmentation Realignment (LSR) with a team of 8 developers (Python, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib)

- Web Application: Indian Tax & Accounting Solutions: End to end product development lifecycle for Indian tax & accounting solutions which involved business case preparation, project charting, cost management, scheduling, resource planning, development & monitoring and deployment (MVC.Net, REST API, SQL Server)
- Database Development & Support: Database design for Tax & Accounting solutions, Production Deployment and Support (SQL Server, SSIS, SSRS)

• Satyam Computers

Hyderabad, India

Database Analyst

Dec 2007 - May 2009

o Microsoft Corporation License Generation: Analyzing day by day issues form the business and involve developers for any change request. Building SQL queries for data extraction for exploratory analysis. (SQL Server, SSAS, SSRS)

• Hewlett Packard

Singapore

Database Consultant

May 2007 - Nov 2007

o Database Migration: Database Migration from SQL 2000 to SQL 2005 and Testing. Database growth, owner and compatibility setting, Maintenance Plan and Backup job creation

• Wipro Technologies

Hyderabad, India

Project Engineer

June 2005 - May 2007

o Database Development: New application design, development and implementation, T-SQL coding like SP, View, Function etc. Implementing and Fine tuning Database and web application

• Rightwave Infosolutions

NOIDA, India

Database Engineer

Feb 2005 - June 2005

o Database Development: Worked on Data modeling, Managing databases, Database backup/restore, Data Import/Export, Performance tuning, writing Procedure, Functions, Triggers and complex queries. Worked on high availability solutions.

• Electrobug Technology

Gurgaon, India

Database Engineer

Sep 2004 - Feb 2005

- o SQL Server DBA: Worked on Data modeling, Managing databases, Database backup/restore, Data Import/Export, Performance tuning, writing Procedure, Functions, Triggers and complex queries. Worked on high availability solutions.
- Resource Center for Indian Language and Technology Solutions

New Delhi, India

Jan 2003 - Sep 2004

Programmer

EDUCATION

• Master in Computer Applications

Vidyasagar University

Midnapore, West Bengal, India

Dec. 1999 - Jan. 2003

• Bachelor of Science in Computer Application

Hijli College

Kharagpur, West Bengal, India

Sept. 1996 - Sept. 1999

CERTIFICATION

- 2020 Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure by Coursera
- 2020 Google Cloud Platform Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals by Coursera
- 2019 Machine Learning for Engineering and Science Applications by NPTEL & IIT Madras
- 2018 Prince2 Agile Foundation Certificate in Agile Project Management by AXLEOS UK

Interests